<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook V5.0//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/docbook.dtd">
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
	<title>PHP</title>
	<section id="{@id php_comments}">
		<title>Comments</title>
		<para>
			USE ASSERTS!
		</para>
		
		<para>
			Non-documentation comments are strongly encouraged.
			A general rule of thumb is that if you look at a section of code and think 
			"Wow, I don't want to try and describe that", 
			you need to comment it before you forget how it works.
		</para>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>C++ style comments (/* */) and standard C comments (//) are both acceptable.</listitem>
				<listitem>Use of perl/shell style comments (#) is prohibited.</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<section id="{@id php_comments_phpdoctags}">
			<title>PHPdoc Tags</title>
			<para>
				Inline documentation for classes should follow the PHPDoc convention, 
				similar to Javadoc. More information about PHPDoc can be found here:
			</para>
			<para>
				{@link http://www.phpdoc.org/}
			</para>
		</section>	
		<section id="{@id php_comments_filecomments}">
			<title>File Comments</title>
			<para>
				Every file should start with a comment block describing its purpose,
				version, author, package, subpackage, license and a copyright 
				message. The comment block should be a block comment in standard 
				JavaDoc format along with a SVN Id tag. While all JavaDoc tags are 
				allowed, only the tags in the examples below will be parsed by 
				PHPdoc.				
			</para>
			<para>
				corelib contains a mixed copyright. For files which contains
				code from other projects like pear og pecl copyright and license
				for both corelib and the source of the code must be specified.
			</para>
			<para>
			    <programlisting language="php">
				    <![CDATA[
/* vim: set tabstop=4 shiftwidth=4 softtabstop=4: */						
/**
 * brief description.
 * long description.  more long description.
 *
 * @author Steffen Sørensen <ss@corelib.org>
 * @copyright Copyright (c) 2005-2008 Back in five minutes
 * @license http://www.bravura.dk/licence/corelib_1_0/
 * @package corelib
 * @subpackage Base
 * @link http://www.corelib.org/
 * @version 4.0.0 ($Id: Base.php 3382 2006-11-08 11:02:41Z wayland $)
 */					    ]]>
			    </programlisting>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="{@id php_comments_classcomments}">
			<title>Function and Class Comments</title>
			<para>
				Similarly, every function should have a block comment 
				specifying name, parameters, return values, and last 
				change date, etc.				
			</para>
			<para>
			    <programlisting language="php">
				    <![CDATA[
/**
 * brief description.
 * long description.  more long description.
 *
 * @package corelib
 * @subpackage Base
 */					    
	 						]]>
			    </programlisting>
			</para>				
		</section>			
		<section>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>
				The placement of periods in the short and long descriptions is important to the PHPdoc parser.
				The first period always ends the short description. 
				All future periods are part of the long description, ending with a blank comment line. 
				The long comment is optional.
			</para>
		</section>			
	</section>
	
	<!--
		INDENTING START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_indenting}">
		<title>Indenting</title>
		<para>
			All indenting is done with TABS. Before committing any file to SVN,
			make sure you first replace spaces with tabs and verify the formatting.
		</para>
	</section>


	<!--
		PHP CODE TAGS STRUCTURE START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_phpcodetags}">
		<title>PHP Code Tags</title>
		<para>
			Always use &lt;?php ?&gt; to delimit PHP code, not the &lt;? ?&gt; shorthand. This is required for corelib
			compliance and is also the most portable way to include PHP code on differing operating systems and setups.
		</para>
	</section>
	
		
	<!--
		CONTROL STRUCTURE START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_expressions}">
		<title>Expressions</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>Use parentheses liberally to resolve ambiguity.</listitem>
				<listitem>Using parentheses can force an order of evaluation. This saves the time a reader may spend remembering precedence of operators.</listitem>
				<listitem>Don't sacrifice clarity for cleverness.</listitem>
				<listitem>Write conditional expressions so that they read naturally aloud.</listitem>
				<listitem>Sometimes eliminating a not operator (!) will make an expression more understandable.</listitem>
				<listitem>Keep each line simple.</listitem>
				<listitem>The ternary operator (x ? 1 : 2) usually indicates too much code on one line. if... else if... else is usually more readable.</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="{@id php_control_structure}">
		<title>Control Structures</title>
		<para>
			These include if, for, while, switch, etc. Here is an example if statement, 
			since it is the most complicated form:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
if ( ( condition1 ) || ( condition2 ) ) {
    action1;
} elseif ( ( condition3 ) && ( condition4 ) ) {
    action2;
} else {
    defaultaction;
}
					]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>
			Control statements shall have one space between the control 
			keyword and opening parenthesis, to distinguish them from function calls.
		</para>
		<para>
			You are strongly encouraged to always use curly braces even in situations 
			where they are technically optional. Having them increases readability and 
			decreases the likelihood of logic errors being introduced when new 
			lines are added.
		</para>
		<para>
			For switch statements:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
switch ( condition ) {
    case 1: {
        action1;
        break;
    }
    case 2: {
        action2;
        break;
    }
    default: {
        defaultaction;
        break;
    }
}
					]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	
	<!--
		FUNCTION CALLS START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_indenting}">
		<title>Function Calls</title>
		<para>
			Functions should be called with no spaces between the function name, 
			the opening parenthesis, and the first parameter; spaces between commas 
			and each parameter, and no space between the last parameter, the closing 
			parenthesis, and the semicolon. Here's an example:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
$var = foo($bar, $baz, $quux);
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>		
		<para>
			As displayed above, there should be one space on either side of an equals sign used 
			to assign the return value of a function to a variable. In the case of a block of 
			related assignments, more space may be inserted to promote readability:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
$short         = foo($bar);
$long_variable = foo($baz);
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>		
	</section>	
	
	<!--
		FUNCTION DECLARATION START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_function_declarations}">
		<title>Function Declarations</title>
		<para>
			Functions should be called with no spaces between the function name, 
			the opening parenthesis, and the first parameter; spaces between commas 
			and each parameter, and no space between the last parameter, the closing 
			parenthesis, and the semicolon. Here's an example:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
function funstuff_system( $field ) {
	$system["description"] = t( "This module inserts funny text into posts randomly." );
	return $system[$field];
}
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>		
		<para>
			Arguments with default values go at the end of the argument list. 
			Always attempt to return a meaningful value from a function if one is appropriate.
		</para>
	</section>		
	
	<!--
		ARRAYS START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_arrays}">
		<title>Arrays</title>
		<para>
			Arrays should be formatted with a space separating each element and assignment operator, if applicable:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
$some_array = array( 'hello', 'world', 'foo' => 'bar' );
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>		
		<para>
			Note that if the line spans longer than 80 characters , each element should be broken into its own line,
			and indented one level:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
$array[] = array(
	'type' => 'textfield',
	'size' => 60,
	'maxlength' => 128,
);
	
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>
			Note the comma at the end of the last array element; This is not a typo! It helps prevent parsing errors 
			if another element is placed at the end of the list later.
		</para>
	</section>		
	
	<!--
		NAMING CONVENTIONS START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions}">
		<title>Naming Conventions</title>
		<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions_functions_and_methods}">
			<title>Functions and Methods</title>
			<para>
				Functions and methods should be named using lowercase and words should be separated with an underscore. 
				Functions should in addition have the grouping/module name as a prefix, to avoid name collisions between modules.
			</para>
			<para>
				Private class members (meaning class members that are intended to be used only from within the same class in which 
				they are declared; PHP 4 does not support truly-enforceable private namespaces) are preceded by a single underscore. 
				For example:
			</para>
			<para>
				<programlisting language="php">
					<![CDATA[
_node_get()
$this->_status
						]]>				
				</programlisting>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions_constants}">
			<title>Constants</title>
			<para>
				Constants should always be all-uppercase, with underscores to separate words. This includes pre-defined PHP constants 
				like TRUE, FALSE, and NULL. Prefix module-defined constant names with the uppercased name of the module they are a part of.
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions_global_variables}">
			<title>Global Variables</title>
			<para>
				If you need to define global variables, their name should start with a single underscore followed by the 
				module/theme name and another underscore.
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions_class_names}">
			<title>Class Names</title>
			<para>
				Classes should be given descriptive names. Avoid using abbreviations where possible. Class names should always begin with an uppercase letter.
			</para>
			<para>
				<programlisting language="php">
					<![CDATA[
$type = new stdClass();
						]]>				
				</programlisting>
			</para>			
		</section>

		<section id="{@id php_naming_conventions_filenames}">
			<title>Filenames</title>
			<para>
				All documentation files should have the filename extension ".txt" to make viewing them on Windows systems easier. 
				Also, the filenames for such files should be all-caps (e.g. README.txt instead of readme.txt) while the extension 
				itself is all-lowercase (i.e. txt instead of TXT).
			</para>
			<para>
				Examples: README.txt, INSTALL.txt, TODO.txt, CHANGELOG.txt etc.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<!--
		STRING CONCATENATIONS START HERE
	-->
	<section id="{@id php_string_concatenations}">
		<title>String concatenations</title>
		<para>
			Always use a space between the dot and the concatenated part, unless it is a quote. So there is no space 
			between the dot and the quote..
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
	$string = 'Foo'. $bar;
	$string = $bar .'foo';
	$string = bar() .'foo';
?>
				]]>				
		</programlisting>
	</para>				
	<para>
			When you concatenate simple variables, you can use double quotes and add the string inside, otherwise use single quotes.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
	$string = "Foo $bar";
?>
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			When concatenating two quoted strings together, use a space on both sides of the dot for readability.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
	$string = 'foo' . 'bar';
?>
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			When using the concatenating assignment operator ('.='), use a space on each side as with the assignment operator:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
$string .= 'Foo';
$string .= $bar;
$string .= baz();
?>
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
	</section>
	
	<section id="{@id php_e_all_code}">
		<title>Write E_ALL compliant code</title>
		<para>
			This document is a very recent addition to the coding guidelines, and is still subject to discussion among developers. 
			Do NOT post comments on this page yet. One issue will be created for each point introduced here. 
			Those issues will be used for discussion and patch submission. I'll keep updating this page as the discussion progresses. 
			When a consensus has been reached on each point, this introduction will be deleted. Eventually, when everything has been 
			patched up, I'll delete the mention about Drupal not being E_STRICT compliant.
		</para>
		<section id="{@id php_e_all_code_better_practice}">
			<title>E_ALL: a better practice</title>
			<para>
				Currently, the Drupal code is not E_STRICT compliant. When running a Drupal site with E_ALL, 
				each page view creates scores of error notices messages. Many developers agree that it would be 
				good if the source of Drupal could be brought up to par with commonly accepted good practice.
			</para>
			<para>
				The purpose of this document is twofold:
			</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>to show common coding mistakes that prevent Drupal from being E_STRICT compliant.</listitem>
					<listitem>to set better coding guidelines to use in new code and patches.</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>	
			<para>
				Once those guidelines are accepted, it is only a matter of time and some developers' efforts before all the 
				previous coding mistakes are patched up. Then, we will be able to run Drupal with the E_ALL directive.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="{@id php_common_mistakes}">
		<title>Common coding mistakes and new coding practice</title>
		<para>
			If you want to test if an array has been set to any value, don't use:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
if ($foo) {}
?>					
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			but:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
// either
if (isset($foo)) {} // $foo=0 (zero) and $foo= '' return TRUE
// or
if (!empty($foo)) {} // use this when 0 or '' are not expected
// and are not valid values for $foo.
?>				
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			The difference between isset() and !empty() is that unlike !empty(), isset() 
			will return TRUE even if the variable is set to an empty string or to the integer 0. 
			In order to decide which one to use, consider whether 0 or '' are valid and expected 
			values for your variable.
		</para>
		<para>
			The following code is wrong:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
function _form_builder($form, $parents = array(), $multiple = FALSE) {
	// (...)
	if ($form['#input']) {
		// some code (...)
	}
}
?>			
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			Here, the variable $form is passed on to the function. If $form['#input'] has been set to any value, 
			some code is executed. The problem is that testing this way outputs the following error message:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
notice: Undefined index:  #input in includes/form.inc on line 194.
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
		<para>
			Even though the array $form is already declared and passed to the function, each array's index must be explicitly declared. 
			The previous code should read:
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="php">
				<![CDATA[
<?php
function _form_builder($form, $parents = array(), $multiple = FALSE) {
	// (...)
	if (!empty($form['#input'])) {
		// some code (...)
	}
}
?>
					]]>				
			</programlisting>
		</para>				
	</section>	
</section>